Okay. So, um what I'm going to show you
next is how you could use those that
query selector that I showed you in the
previous um video to dynamically show
some content on the screen. So, here
we've got this dialogue and I've set it
to be open and I've given it a
placeholder title, some placeholder
text, and a closing placeholder text.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to
show you what that web page looks like.
So here I've got this nice black square
with placeholder title, placeholder
text, and a placeholder close button.
And what I'd like to do is I'd like to
make it show dynamically. So rather than
just hard coding it to be open, I would
like to make it show dynamically.
Well, when they click the show modal
button, um it's going to call this
function. And in this function, I'm
going to use document.query selector.
And I am going to look for a dialogue
because that will target all of that
text right there. And what I want to do
is I want to do show modal
and that is a built-in function to this
dialogue. So anytime you have a dialogue
tag, you can call show modal on it and
it will show it as a popup and it will
slightly gray out the rest of the
string. So, if I click show modal, you
can see the background changed slightly
and I've got placeholder title,
placeholder modal text, and this close
modal text. But when I click it, it
doesn't do anything. So, if we want to
make the close work, we use
document.query
selector, and we'll select our dialogue
again, and we'll call the close
function.
And now, when we click show modal, it
pops up. When we click close modal, it
closes. Then we can go back to editing
our screen. Well, we could actually make
this dynamic. So I am going to put in um
input
text* 3. And that gives me three text
inputs. Um I'm going to give this one
the name of title and an ID of title.
And the next one a name of
text and an ID of text. And then the
last one, a name of close
and an ID of close. Okay. So if I save
that and I come to my HTML page, I can
see that I have these three
different inputs.
So
what I'm going to do under this show
modal before I show the modal I need to
get a name
and
a text and a close text.
So name is we're going to look for uh
we're going to go docu whoa not doc type
document doquery selector
and I'm going to search for the one with
the ID of title
and I'm going to set name equal to
document.query query selector title dot
um value
and I'm going to copy this line
and I'm going to paste it in
both those locations
and then I'm going to change this one
from title to text and this one from
title to
close. So that will grab
each of these inputs
and it will grab the ID close text and
title and it'll go in and grab their
values. Okay, once we've got that, I
want to change their placeholder values
here. Well, the way I can do that is I
can say uh document.query query selector
and I am looking for not just the
dialogue but directly in the dialogue I
am looking for the H1 tag and I'm going
to set its inner text equal to the name
they gave me then I'm going to query
select the dialogue P tag and I'm going
to set its inner text equal to the text
and And I'm going to
select the dialogue. And directly inside
the dialogue, there's a button. And I
want to set its inner text to be equal
to
close text.
And then finally, once all that's done,
I want to show the modal. So if we come
over here, uh we could give it a title
of hello world. uh text of this is my
first message and a closing button of
close this dialogue. Now if I click show
modal, it says hello world. This is my
first message and close this dialogue.
Now we have a fully customizable model
that we can show and we are able to
access and edit it all using query
selectors.